The future favors the brave.
Captain America: Brave New World is a action, thriller,
science fiction film directed by Julius Onah.
After meeting with newly elected U.S.
President Thaddeus Ross, Sam finds himself in the
middle of an international incident.
He must discover the reason behind a nefarious global plot before
the true mastermind has the entire world seeing red.
Sam Wilson / Captain America, played by Anthony Mackie.
President Thaddeus Ross, played by Harrison Ford.
Joaquin Torres, played by Danny Ramirez.
Ruth Bat-Seraph, played by Shira Haas.
Samuel Sterns, played by Tim Blake Nelson.
Isaiah Bradley, played by Carl Lumbly.
Captain America: Brave New World is a 2025 American superhero film based on
Marvel Comics featuring the character Sam Wilson / Captain America.
Produced by Marvel Studios and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures, it is the fourth installment in the Captain America film series, a
continuation of the television miniseries The Falcon and the Winter Soldier (2021), and the 35th film in the Marvel Cinematic Universe (MCU).
The film was directed by Julius Onah from a screenplay by Rob Edwards and the
writing teams of Malcolm Spellman & Dalan Musson and Onah & Peter Glanz.
It stars Anthony Mackie as Sam Wilson / Captain America alongside Danny Ramirez, Shira Haas, Carl
Lumbly, Xosha Roquemore, Giancarlo Esposito, Liv Tyler, Tim Blake Nelson, and Harrison Ford.
In the film, Wilson investigates a conspiracy involving U.S.
president Thaddeus Ross (Ford).
Captain America: Civil War (2016) ended the Captain America trilogy starring Chris Evans as Steve
Rogers, and Wilson becomes the new Captain America in The Falcon and the Winter Soldier.
Series writers Spellman and Musson were writing a new Captain America
film by April 2021, and Mackie signed on that August.
Onah joined in July 2022, when the title Captain
America: New World Order was announced.
Additional cast members joined later that year.
Nelson and Tyler returned from the second MCU film, The Incredible Hulk (2008), while Ford replaced William Hurt
as Ross following Hurt's death in March 2022; Ross becomes the superpowered Red Hulk in the film.
Filming took place from March to June 2023 at Trilith Studios in
Atlanta, Georgia, with additional filming in Washington, D.C.
The subtitle was changed to Brave New World during filming.
Matthew Orton joined in December 2023 to write for reshoots, which took place
between May and November 2024, and added Esposito to the film.
The involvement of Edwards and Glanz was revealed that December.
Captain America: Brave New World premiered on February 11, 2025, at the TCL Chinese Theatre in Hollywood, Los
Angeles, and was released in the United States on February 14 as part of Phase Five of the MCU.
It grossed $415 million worldwide.
The film received mixed reviews from critics for its story,
connections to other MCU projects, and visual effects.
The performances, particularly those of Mackie and Ford, received praise.
The film explores themes of hero, usa president, the
white house, superhero, based on comic.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.